Thomas Seropian

French nationality
Currently based in London, United Kingdom

thomas@seropian.io https://uk.linkedin.com/in/tseropian

Tech Lead / Senior Software Engineer

Profile

I am a software engineer with 15 years of experience in building tech and innovation solutions across several startups, nonprofits, and consultancies. I help organisations to apply new ranges of technologies to solve challenging real-world problems with a strong entrepreneurial focus, and ultimately to build and launch successful products that customers love.

Work experience

Senior Backend Stack Engineer (contract based)

Progressive Content, London, United Kingdom – Since Sept. 2020 (progressivecontent.com)

→ Building a microservices backend for the content marketing CMS of a UK based banking client.

Writing code and delivering new features. Integration with 3rd party services. Managing cloud-based infrastructure-as-code platforms and deployments.

→ <u>Technology:</u> Serverless, TypeScript, GraphQL, Node.js, Docker, Jenkins, Terraform, Azure, AWS, ElasticSearch.

Tech Advisor / CTO for an early-stage startup, building interactive education solutions for kids. London, United Kingdom – February to July 2020

The startup generator Antler invited me to work on an early-stage tech-related business model. The Project ended prematurely because of a lack of funding and tractions from users.

→ <u>Technology:</u> Node.js, Webflow, Post-it notes, whiteboard, sharpies, stickers.

Lead Backend Engineer (contract based)

AND Digital, London, United Kingdom – July 2019 to January 2020 (<u>www.and.digital</u>) Leading a development team part of a cloud transformation project for a UK insurance client.

Writing code and delivering new features for an end-user web application. Managing integration with 3rd party back-office services (both REST and SOAP). Refining user stories. Code reviews. Agile (SCRUM) delivery.

 \rightarrow <u>Technology:</u> Serverless, TypeScript, Express, Node.js, React, Docker, Kubernetes, Azure, REST, SOAP.

Head of Engineering for a health-tech startup

Skin Analytics, London, United Kingdom – October 2017 to May 2019 (www.skin-analytics.com)

→ Responsible for clients, internal and commercial applications and infrastructures

Managing applications, cloud infrastructure and releases. Defining roadmaps and priorities and scoping new requirements. Writing code. Hiring and leading technical team (8 members between London and Poland). Day to day management, code reviews and testing. Delivered a Software as a Medical Device commercial API.

→ <u>Technology:</u> AWS, Node.js, TypeScript, React, React Native, MySQL, MongoDB, Docker, Jenkins, Ansible.

Mentor and Advisor, since 2018

→ Mentoring for the tech lead curriculum for the primary french online education platform Open Classrooms

Technical Lead (contract based) for an international online media publishing group

Jamie Oliver, London, United Kingdom – February to September 2017 (www.jamieoliver.com)

→ Responsible for infrastructure and web applications supporting Jamie's online presence.

Scoping migration from a legacy SOAP CRM system to a micro-services new system. Designing and delivering components. Managing contractors and permanent developers. Responsible for new AWS infrastructure.

→ <u>Technology:</u> AWS, Node.js, TypeScript, PHP (Laravel), RESTful APIs, Redis, Solr, Vue.js, WordPress, Varnish.

Team Leader / Technology Manager for an international NGO

Internews London, United Kingdom – April 2015 to December 2016 (www.internews.org)

- → Leading the design, development, and delivery of innovation and technology components

 Working with a multidisciplinary team supporting local startups among the most repressive regimes. Leading on delivering news publishing apps. Managing activities' budgets. Speaking at conferences and events.
- → Managing technology team and resources across multiple projects (8 countries)

 Overseeing the recruitment and day-to-day managing a team of 5 technologists. Ensuring planning, setting priorities, agreeing on detailed work plans, budgets, and schedules. Coaching and mentoring team members. Agile delivery. Responsible for technical architecture and roadmap. Focus on scalability & security.
- → <u>Technology:</u> Node.js, PHP (Laravel), WordPress, Drupal (7/8), Ansible, Nginx, OpenVPN, encryption.

ICT Projects Manager / Web Application Engineer for an international NGO Internews Paris, France / London, United Kingdom - March 2009 to March 2015 (www.internews.org)

→ Online freedom of expression, support of local media, digital security

Designing, developing & supporting multilingual web applications, custom modules. Integration with social network (Twitter, Facebook) APIs. Writing documentation for users. Managing localization, training & support. Writing user stories & specifications. Managing external contractors and developers, resources & infrastructures: Deployment and monitoring of servers, secure hosting & video platforms. Building & delivering and facilitating training & trainers: website building and digital security (West Africa, MENA).

→ <u>Technology</u>: Drupal, Mediawiki, XML/JSON, PHP (OOP, MVC), MySQL, Solr, AWS, Collectd, Vagrant, Nginx.

Software Engineer for a social networking service designed for a family use **Hellotipi.com** Paris, France – February 2008 to January 2009 (www.hellotipi.com)

Designed and developed new features (Video sharing. Photo tagging. Registration process). User support.

→ <u>Technology</u>: Debian, Apache, MySQL, PHP5 (OOP, MVC), XML, Jquery, Ffmpeg.

ICT Projects Manager for a local NGO in Armenia
Fondation KASA Yerevan, Armenia - March 2006 to September 2007 (www.kasa.am)

Coordinated Computer training in youth training centres. Developed activities in the two major cities. Managed the recruitment of the local team. Provided technical support for training & social programs.

Assistant Projects Manager for e-training IT projects for an international training centre **Valeo Thermal Systems** Paris, France – March 2005 to February 2006 (www.valeo.com) Designed & implemented tools for course supports creation (virtual classes, e-learning modules).

Education

MSc in Computer Sciences and Innovation

Ecole Supérieure d'Informatique, Electronique, Automatique Paris, France

5 years engineering school in information technologies & electronics (www.esiea.fr).

 \rightarrow Graduated with first-class honours.

Foreign languages

French: Mother tongue English: Fluent Spanish: Basic level Arabic: Beginner

Hobbies

Collecting records (LPs), mostly nerdy noisy music. Photography (film and digital). Part of the media team of a

non-league fan-owned football club in East London.